Guide to the Albert Leroy Andrews correspondence, 1899-1964.
Andrews, Albert Leroy correspondence, 1899-1964.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Albert Leroy Andrews correspondence, 1899-1964.
3849
Albert Leroy Andrews, 1878-1964.
2.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence reflecting Andrews' expertise in the field of bryology includes inquiries from hobbyists and scholars for determinations of mosses and liverworts; requests by scientific journals for papers and critical analyses of published articles; questions from botanical agencies and societies, government departments, and major academic institutions around the world.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Albert Leroy Andrews was a Professor of Germanic Philology at Cornell University, an amateur bryologist, and Honorary Curator of the Wiegand Herbarium.
CHRONOLOGY
1899 Attended Williams College, BA
1899-1901 Taught Preparatory School in Vermont
1901-1902 Assistant Principal of a Prep. School in Mt. Pleasant, PA
1902 Awarded MA by Williams College, for work done in absentia
1902-1903 MA from Harvard Graduate College
1903-1904 Instructor of German at University of West Virginia
1904-1905 Instructor of German at Dartmouth College
1905-1908 Studied abroad at Universities in Berlin, Kiel, Copenhagen, and Christiania (Oslo), and received Ph.D. from University of Kiel in 1908
1908 Teaching fellow at Cornell
1909 Instuctor in German and Scandinavian languages at Cornell
1918 Assistant Professor of German (some references say 1919)
1924-1928 Chairman of German Department
1931 Professor of Germanic Philology
1946 Retired with the title of Professor of Germanic Philology Emeritus
1953 Named Honorary Curator of the Bryological Collections of the Wiegand Herbarium of Cornell University
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence reflecting Andrews' expertise in the field of bryology includes inquiries from hobbyists and scholars for determinations (identifications) of mosses and liverworts; requests by scientific journals for publishable papers and critical analyses of published articles (including The Bryologist, for which Andrews served as Associate Editor from 1938-1949, and the Revue Bryologique edited by Pierre Allorge); questions from botanical agencies and societies, government departments, and major academic institutions around the world. Correspondents include Lewis E. Anderson, John Hendley Barnhart, Hugo L. Blomquist, N.L. Britton, Stewart H. Burnham, Henry S. Conard, Howard A. Crum, W.G. Farlow, A.J. Grout, Leopold Loeske, William R. Maxon, C.L. Porter, Geneva Sayre (President of the American Bryological Society), William Campbell Steere, William Randolph Taylor, Roland Thaxter, C. Warnsdorf, Winona Welch, and numerous others.
CORRESPONDENTS
Correspondents of Andrews include those in charge of botanical agencies and societies, government departments and major institutes around the world. These include:
Ammons, Nelle
Professor at University of West Virginia
Anderson, Lewis E.
An important bryologist from Duke University
Astorino, Oswaldo
Botanist, from Brazil
Bailey, L.H.
First Director at Cornell
Baldwin, M.M.
With the American Red Cross
Barnhart, John Hendley
N.Y. Botanical Garden Biographer
Benedict, Ralph C.
Brooklyn Botanical Garden
Blomquist, Hugo L.
Professor at Duke University
Bomhard, Mirian L.
U.S. Department of Agriculture - Forest Service
Bray, William L.
State College of Forestry at Syracuse
Brinkman, A.H.
A student of bryology from Canada
Britton, Elizabeth G. and N.L.
First Director of N.Y. Botanical Gardens, and his wife (Elizabeth)
Burnham, Stewart H.
N.Y. State Education Department in the Science Division, also at Cornell for 20 years, 1923-1943
Burrell, W.H.
The University, Leeds
Collins, J. Franklin
Professor from Brown University
Conard, Henry S.
Professor at Grinnell College, Iowa and an important bryologist
Crum, Howard A.
Professor at University of Michigan, and an important bryologist
Dalby, D.H.
British Museum of National History, Department of Botany
Durand, Elias J.
Professor at University of Missouri
Evans, Alexander W.
Osborn Botanical Lab, Yale University
Farlow, W.G.
Harvard, Herbarium and Laboratories of Cryptogamic Botany
Fearnsides, Marguerite
Botany School of Cambridge, England
Fernald, M.L.
Gray Herbarium, Harvard - the Director
Ferris, Roxanna S.
Stanford University Herbarium
Frye, Theodore C.
Professor of the University of Washington at Seattle
Fulford, Margaret
Proessor at the University of Cincinnati
Grout, A.J.
Like Andrews, Grout was not a full-time bryologist, but was well known and respected for his knowledge in the field
Hagerup, O.
Botanisk Museum, Denmark
Harkness, Hilda
Department of Mines, National Museum of Canada
Hattori, Sinske
Hattori Botanical Lab - Japan
Hermann, Fred J.
U.S. Department of Agriculture
Hilferty, Frank J.
Student from Harvard
Holzinger, John M.
Winona, Minnesota State Normal School
Hyland, Fay
Professor at University of Maine at Orono
Lantham, Roy
Amateur naturalist from Long Island
Lawton, Elva
Professor at Hunter College, N.Y. and University of Washington at Seattle
Loeske, Leopold
Important European bryologist
Long, Bayard
The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
Maguire, Bassett
Utah State Agriculture College
Maxon, William R.
Director of Smithsonian Institution, United States Museum
Millspaugh, C.F.
Field Museum of National History in Chicago
Moldenke, Harold N.
Curator of N.Y. Botanical Garden
Moore, H. Emery, Jr.
Professor at Cornell
Morton, C.V.
Curator of the Division of Cryptogams at Smithsonian Institute
Munz, P.A.
Pomona College, Professor of Botany
Nicholas, George E.
Scheffield Scientific School of Yale University
Patterson, Paul M.
Hollins College at Virgina, Professor
Porsild, A.E.
Botanist, National Herbarium of Canada
Porter C.L.
The University of Wyoming, Department of Botany, Sullivant Moss Society - publishers of The Bryologist
Robinson, B.L.
Early director of Gray Herbarium, Harvard
Rogers, Donald P.
N.Y. Botanical Garden
Rollins, Reed C.
Director Gray Herbarium, Harvard
Rogerson, Clark T.
N.Y. Botanical Garden, Bronx - Curator of The Cryptogamic Herbarium
Rousseau, Jacques
Director of Montreal Botanical Garden
Sargent, C.S.
Director of Arnold Arboretum, Harvard
Sayre, Geneva
The American Bryological Society, President
Schumacher, Alb.
German Botanist
Schuster, Rudolf M.
Professor at Duke University
Seaver, Fred J.
Head Curator of N.Y. Botanical Garden
Sharp, Aaron Jack
Professor of Botany, University of Tennessee at Knoxville
Skutch, Alexander F.
Ornithologist from Costa Rica
Small, John K.
Curator N.Y. Botanical Garden, Bronx
Smith, Stanley Jay
The University of the State of N.Y. Senior Curator of Botany at Albany
Steere, William Campbell
Director of N.Y. Botanical Garden, President of the Garden and Dean of Amherst College
Stormer, Per
Botanical Museum, Norway
Taylor, Wm. Randolph
University of Pennsylvania and an importany bryologist
Thaxtor, Roland
Important bryologist from Harvard
Warnsdorf, C.
Bryologist from Denmark
Weber, William A.
Curator of the Herbarium at Bolder, University of Colorado
Welch, Winona H.
Depauw University of Greencastle, India
Wiegand, K.M.
Head of Department of Botany at Cornell
Winne, William T.
Professor of Biology, a Cornell graduate and amateur bryologist
SUBJECTS
Names:
Andrews, Albert Le Roy, 1878-1964.; Anderson, Lewis Edward, b.1912.; Barnhart, John Hendley.; Blomquist, Hugo L.; Britton, Nathaniel Lord, 1859-1934.; Burnham, Stewart H.; Conard, Henry Shoemaker, b.1874.; Crum, Howard Alvin, 1922-; Farlow, W.G.; Grout, A.J.; Loeske, Leopold.; Maxon, William R.; Porter, C.L.; Sayre, Geneva.; Steere, William Campbell, b.1907.; Taylor, William Randolph, b.1895.; Warnsdorf, C.; Welch, Winona.
Titles:
The Bryologist.; Revue Bryologique.
Subjects:
Bryology.; College teachers.; Bryologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence on Bryology
This correspondence concerns Andrews' avocation as a bryologist and consists primarily of inquires from hobbyists and scholars for determinations (identifications) of mosses and liveworts; requests by scientific journals for publishable papers and critical analyses of published articles (including such journals as The Bryologist, which Andrews served as Associate Editor for the years 1938-1949, and the Revue Bryologique edited by Pierre Allorge); questions from those in charge of botanical agencies and societies, government departments, and major institutes around the world due to Andews' expertise in the field of bryology; includes several photographs of Andrews (as indicated in index)
Material is arranged first alphabetically by correspondent and then chronologically with that order. Also included (Box 8, folder 49) is an alphabetical listing of correspondence concerning notes and questions to Andrews about the determination of bryological specimens (photocopied from original slip lists) Boxes 1-8
Series II. Family Correspondence
The correspondence (1905-1907), primarily from Andrews' sister Mabel and his mother Abbie L. Andrews concerns personal and family questions, including the sale of the family home and farm in Williamstown, Massachusettes and his father's tragic suicide in 1905, Mabel's marriage to Rev. Francais Treadway Clayton in Nov. 1906, and on letter dated Sept. 2, 1907, which mentions a sermon made by Booker T. Washington in the Congregational Church.
There are also twenty-two letters to Andrews from his sons, Harold, Frank, and Ralph, daughter Helga, and daughters-in-law Ellen and Hetty from 1948-1961 about family concerns, including the death of Andrews' wife, Olga, on Apr. 17, 1960. Material is arranged chronologically. Box 9
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence on Bryology
  - Adams, Cleora D., 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alan, H.H., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allard, Harry A., July 18, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allorge, Pierre, 1929-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allorge, Madame P., 1944-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alteri, Charlotte H., Sept. 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Bryological Society, Sept. 6, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ammons, Nelle, 1929-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, Lewis E., 135-19619 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrews, Lucia M., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anrep, Aleph V., 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anselm, Br. M., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Astorino, Oswaldo, July 21, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Babbitt, Ruth Varie, Jan. 23, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bailey, John W., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bailey, L.H., Jan. 20, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baker, Charles L., Mar. 10, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baker, Frances (picture), 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baldwin, M.M., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barnhart, John Hendley, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barlett, Harley Harris, 1909-1912 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bartram, Edwin B., 1922-1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Beals, A. Tennyson (pictures), 1920-1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Beaulac, Alderic, Aug. 15, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Becking, Rudy W., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bellefeuille, Robert, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Benedict, Ralph C., June 22, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bergethon, K. Roald, Jan. 20, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Best, G.N., 1902-1909 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bird, Charles D., 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bizot, Maurice, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Blomquist, Hugo L. (includes letters of E. Abbe to Blomquist), 1930-1961; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Boardman, Charles M., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bodenberg, E.T., 1936-1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bomhard, Miriam L., July 29, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Borkland, Lillian, Mar. 14, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bray, William L., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Breen, Ruth S., 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brinkman, A.H. (originals and xeroxes), 1912-1945 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Britton, Elizabeth G., 1903-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Britton, N.L., June 21, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Margaret S., 1925-1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Richard M., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bryan, Virginia, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Burnham, Stewart H., 1910-1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Burrell, W.H., Jan. 10, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bush, B.F., Dec. 23, 1916 (?) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - B., Hans (Andrews' nephew), May 21, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cain, Roy F., Jan. 27, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Calvert, Amelia S., Feb. 15, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Campbell, Ella, Sept. 15, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cardot, J., 1911-1918 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Castle, H., June 7, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chamberlain, Edward B., 1905-1922 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Cheney, Lellen S., 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - [Removed] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chodat, R., Aug. 16, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Christophersen, Erling, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Churchill, Joseph R., Apr. 6, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clark, Daniel G., Dec. 28, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Clarke, John M., Jan. 2, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Clayton, Temple, 1934-1956 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Clebsch, Alfred (includes list), 1946-1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Clifford, T., 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Collins, J. Franklin, 1903-1931 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Conard, Henry S. (includes letters of E. Abbe to Conard), 1929-1960; 1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cooper, Arthur W., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cooper, William S., Sept. 29, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Cornell University Library (acknowledgement), Sept. 23, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Crum, Howard A., 1949-1961 (Box 2, Folder 38-40)
  - Dalby, D.H., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dale, E.M.S., Oct. 4, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Darlington, Henry T., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Ronald B., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Daton, William A., Oct. 4, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Demerio, C.H., 1913-1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dismier, 1912-1914 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dixon, H.N., 1914-1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Drew, William B., 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Drexler, R.V., 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dunham, Elizabeth Marie, 1909-1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dunham, Howard P., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dupret, H., 1912-1916 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Durand, Elias J., 1908-1918 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dusen, K.F., Feb. 1913 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ekblaw, W. Elmer, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Emmitt, Ronald W., May 21, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Erskine, J.S., 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Evans, Alexander W., 1903-1922 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Eyrdam, Walter J., May 23, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Farlow, W.G., 1911-1917 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Fearnsides, Marguerite, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Felippone, Florentino, Dec. 9, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Fernald, M.L., 1911-1921 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Ferris, Roxanna S., July 10, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Fleischer, Max, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Flowers, Seville, 1935-1944 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Foreau, G., Sept. 23, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Friedrichs, Anna, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Frye, Theodore C., 1908-1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Fulford, Margaret, 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Gans, N., Nov. 20, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Garside, S., May 30, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Gaskill, Alfred, Mar. 19, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gier, L.J., 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Giesy, R.M., Sept. 20, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Githens, Thomas S., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Godfrey, R.K., May 4, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gray, Fred W., 1934-1940 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Grobman, Arnold, Nov. 16, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Grout, A.J., 1929-1944 (Box 3, Folder 42-45)
  - Guccion, John, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Gyorffy, Barna, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gyorffy, Istvan, Nov. 30, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Habeeb, Herbert, Dec. 17, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Hadden, Norman G., Mar. 5, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Hagen, I., 1912-1915 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Hagerup, O., 1936-1947 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Hale, Mason E., 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Halliday, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hand, Clarence H., Feb. 7, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Hanson, Herbert C., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Haring, Inez M., 1937-1960 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Harkness, Hilda, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Harvill, A.M., Jr., 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Hattori, Sinske (includes 1 receipt), 1955-1960 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Hausman, Leon A., June 13, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Heilman, Robert A., Jan. 16, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hampel, Gartner K. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Herb, Anselme, Moxley (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hermann, Fred J. (newspaper clipping included), 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Herzog, Th., 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Heusser, Calvin J., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hilferty, Frank J., 1953-1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hill, Arthur W., Jan. 24, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Hill, E.J., Nov. 16, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hochreutiner, B.P.G., Sept. 15, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hoeg, Ove Arbo, 1935-1946 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Holzinger, John M., 1905-1929 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hood, Sameul C. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Horr, Ella L., 1910 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - House, H.D., Jan. 14, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Howard, Richard A., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Howe, Marshall A., Nov. 8, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hubbard, Gerard F., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Huntington, J. Warren, 1901-1903 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Husnot, T., 1915 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hutchinson, Ethel (1 letter received after death date), 1948-1963 (Box 4, Folder 22-24)
  - Hyland, Fay, Apr. 23, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Jaggli, W., 1933-1947 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Jennings, O.E., 1914-1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Jensen, C., 1910-1914 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Jessen, Knud, Apr. 16, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Jewett, H.S., 1912 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Johnson, Eleanor, 1952-1961 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Johnson, T.C., 1904-1905 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Jones, George Neville, Apr. 9, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Jorgensen, E., 1921-1925 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Jovet-Ast, S. (joint letter with Rol, R., both filed under Jovet-Ast, S.), June 16-18, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Kaalaas, B., 1905-1914 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Kaiser, George B., 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Kelly, E. Martin, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Kelly, Rachel, July 15, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Kennedy, Geo. G., 1903-1912 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ketchledge, Edwin H., 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Kiener, Walter, Feb. 3, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Killip, E.P., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Kingman, C.C., 1908-1912 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Kingsbury, Jack and Louise, July 14, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Koch, Leo O., 1948-1958 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Koster, Hollis, 1939-1948 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Kucyniak, James, 1942-1960 (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
  - Lankester, C., 1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Latham, Roy, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Lawton, Elva, 1951-1961 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Leavitt, R.G., Sept. 4, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - LeBlanc, Brother Fabius, 1947-1961 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Le Gallo, C., 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Leonhardt, Otto, Dec. 31, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lepage, Ernest, 1941-1957 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lersten, Nels R., July 12, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Lid, Johannes, 1920-1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lillie, David, 1912-1915 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lindberg, Harold, Nov. 9, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Linder, David H., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Llano, George A., 1950 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Loeske, Leopold (picture included), 1912-1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Long, Bayard, 1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lowe, Rachel L., 1929-1941 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Lowrie, W.M., June 12, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Lutz, H.J., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - MacFadden, Fay A., 1927-1959 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - MacGillivray, F.A., Jan. 28, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Mackaness, Faith Pennebaker (see also: Pennebaker), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Macron, John, Nov. 10, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Maguire, Bassett, 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Malte, M.O., Sept. 6, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Malte, N., Feb. 19, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Mapes, Herbert M., 1950-1961 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Maxon, William R., 1912-1947 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - McAllister, F., 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - McCay, Clive, Mar. 4, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - McCormick, Jack, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - McFarlin, James B., Aug. 13, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - McGregor, Ronald L., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - McIntosh, William, Sept. 25, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Meijer, Wim, 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Melin, Elias, 1912-1915 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Meyer, Carl, Jan. 11, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Meyer, Fred G., Feb. 4, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Meylan, Ch., 1933-1937 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Miller, Harvey A., 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Millspaugh, C.F., 1904-1912 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Mizushima, (Mrs.) Urara, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Moldenke, Harold N., 1944-1949 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Moller, Hj., 1919-1939 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Moore, H. Emery, Jr., June 14, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Moorhead, Helen Howell, Aug. 2, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Morton, C.V., 1951-1958 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Moss, E.H., 1930-1961 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Mouen, Lly, June 14, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Moul, Edwin T., Mar. 20, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Moxley, Eugene A., 1929-1941 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Mulleacan, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Munz, P.A., Oct. 17, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Nanz, Ralph S., Mar. 12, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Natworth, A., July 17, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Naveau, 1929-1934 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Needham, J.G., Feb. 17, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell, June 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - New York State Museum (memorandum of endoresement), Dec. 20, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newbould, P.J., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Newcomer, Stanley, June 26, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Nicholas, George E., 1910-1938 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Nicholson, Wm., 1910-1919 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Noguchi, A., 1949-1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nuttall, Lawrence W., Oct. 1, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ochi, Harumi, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - O'Neill, Hugh, Apr. 1, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Ostenfeld, C.H., 1911-1912 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Osvald, Hugo, Sept. 25, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Otis, Chas. H., 1915-1918 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Owens, Anna Belle, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Papuan-Australian Expedition, c. 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Parlin, John C., 1929-1946 (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
  - Patterson, Paul M., 1929-1956 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Paul, H., Feb. 28, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Pearson, Wm. Hy, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1903-1917 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Pennebaker, Faith (see also Mackaness), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Perkins, Lilly, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Persson, Herman, 1945-1960 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - Porsild, A.E., Aug. 29, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Porter, C.L., 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Porter, John Bonsall, 1915-1917 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Powers, Marie, Jan. 17, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Pratt, Gene A., Nov. 22, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Preston, Jean, May 7, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Pursell, Ronald A., 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Rand, Edward L., 1906-1913 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Rapp, F.W., 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Rapp, S., 1915-1921 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Redfearn, Paul L., Jr., 1949-1961 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Reed, Clyde F., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Reese, William D., 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Reimos, A., Feb. 3, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Richards, Donald, 1939-1949 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Riddle, Gertrude H., 1931-1936 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Riddle, Linclon W., 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Rigg, George B., 1945-1951 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Ritchie, J.C., 1958 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Roberts, C.M., Nov. 16, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 50)